<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Brando in Space]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Brando in Space</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 03:12:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 03:12:08 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Nomai Mask]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><br>Before we get into this little blog post, I want to give you a little bit of background on what a Nomai Mask even is!<br>A Nomai is an alien race from one of my favorite games, Outer Wilds. It is a space exploration game in which you, a Hearthian, travel the dying solar system in an attempt to figure out the mysteries of an ancient alien race (the Nomai) while also with the fun gameplay mechanic of being in a 22 minute time loop! <br>TldrSpace wow look at all this mystery but oh no time loop and now I'm back where I started every 22 minutes!!!<br><img alt="outer-wilds-splash.webp" src="\lib\media\outer-wilds-splash.webp"><br>WarningThis post contains spoilers for the game. If you are interesting in playing Outer Wilds (which I higly recommend!), please play it first and then come back so you stay spoiler free!<br><br>Because I had never used EVA foam or have ever made a mask like this, I mostly followed a tutorial on YouTube by Punished Props (their content is so amazing!) Here is a link to the video:<br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=paLlATF-O34" class="thumbnail"></a><img src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/paLlATF-O34/mqdefault.jpg" class="thumbnail-img"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=paLlATF-O34" class="thumbnail"><div title="Let's Make a NOMAI Mask with FREE Templates! | OUTER WILDS" class="thumbnail-title"></div></a>Let's Make a NOMAI Mask with FREE Templates! | OUTER WILDS<a title="Punished Props Academy" href="https://www.youtube.com/@punishedprops" class="thumbnail-author">Punished Props Academy</a><br>First, I had to cut out all the templates (made by Punished Props) so I can have an easier time cutting the EVA foam. There was a LOT of different pieces and a lot of paper cut!<br><img alt="paper-cutouts.jpg" src="\lib\media\paper-cutouts.jpg" style="width: 700px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Once I had all the templates cut out and ready to go, I started cutting the foam. The first few layers are very rough, as I have never used EVA foam or an exacto knife like this before. The edges are uneven and there are some little strands hanging out but I was still proud of myself for making it!<br><br><img src="\lib\media\step-1.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\step-2.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\step-3.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><br>After I cut out the holes for the 3 eyes, I came across a little dilemma. There is a small little piece that sits inside of the eye hole and sits in the middle of the eye socket. I wasn't sure how my stumpy little hot glue gun was supposed to glue the foam to it and have it not be raised and look like it's floating.<br><img alt="eye-sockets.jpg" src="\lib\media\eye-sockets.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>I ended up figuring out that the little pieces (the ones being pointed to in the image) are snug enough to stay in place without having to glue it. I decided just to roll with it because I wasn't worried about them falling out. They eventually became stuck in place by the primer and paint, but that's later on in the article.<br><br>There are even more parts that go around the eye sockets!! In the image below, the eye on the bottom right shows the smaller eye socket. (You can also see my sloppy cutting and hot gluing job 0-0)<br><img alt="even-smaller-eye-holes.jpg" src="\lib\media\even-smaller-eye-holes.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>I originally wanted this to be a Halloween costume and so I wanted to have the maximum amount of vision possible. Adding the little eye socket piece severely limited my field of vision which is a big whomp whomp when it comes to walking around at night with stairs, bumps, curbs, and little kids to look out for when trick-or-treating.<br><br>It ain't a Nomai mask without it's crazy and overly pretentious six horns!<br><img alt="solanum-does-a-little-spin.gif" src="\lib\media\solanum-does-a-little-spin.gif"><br>There are so many different pieces for the horns that they took me the longest to make. I first cut out all the horn pieces and labeled them with tape so I knew which piece went with the other pieces.<br><img alt="so-many-pieces.jpg" src="\lib\media\so-many-pieces.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>I then began the process of hot-gluing all the pieces together, and they started to look amazingly cool!<br><img src="\lib\media\horns-1.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\horns-2.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;"><br>Here is what the first half of the horns will look like when put together:<br><img alt="half-finished.jpg" src="\lib\media\half-finished.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
Although you can see lots of the messy hot glue and little cutting mistakes, I am so very proud of this image. This was the first time I made something out of foam and I am super duper proud of it!!<br><br>This is what the mask looked like once I had finished cutting and gluing all of the horns:<br><img alt="the-whole-shebang.jpg" src="\lib\media\the-whole-shebang.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>AMAZING!!!!<br>One of the final steps of assembly was to add walls around the base to give it some depth! This was a little tricky and there is a lot of obvious places where hot glue is but it still looks super awesome in my opinion.<br><img alt="got-them-side-walls.jpg" src="\lib\media\got-them-side-walls.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Then I was able to glue all the pieces together and BAM! LOOKING EPIC! (apologies for the unflattering mirror picture)<br><img alt="its-on-my-face.jpg" src="\lib\media\its-on-my-face.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br><br>Before painting, I decided to do a few touch ups.<br>When watching the tutorial by Punished Props, I noticed they were scoring the foam using a knife and drawing small patterns in the foam. I did that too for the detail but I continued to wonder why their scoring looked so good and why mine looked super mediocre. <br>After doing a bit of research, I realized the reason that my scoring looked so wonky was because you're supposed to heat seal the foam with a heat gun!!!!! I TOTALLY OVERLOOKED THAT PART! null<br>I totally didn't think they were using a heated knife at first.<br>Here is a comparison of a little test I did. The left shows what I was originally doing without heat sealing the foam. The right shows what it looks like when it IS heat sealed.<br><img alt="unsealed-vs-sealed.jpg" src="\lib\media\unsealed-vs-sealed.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>HUGE DIFFERENCE!! No wonder I was so confused haha!<br>Here is another comparison of unsealed vs. sealed (top is unsealed, bottom is sealed)<br><img src="\lib\media\comparison-1.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\comparison-2.jpg" style="border-radius: 0px;"><br>The heat seal looks so much nicer!<br>There was a little caveat that I realized when doing it though. When sealing the foam, the heat gun caused the hot glue to start melting!! WHICH IS VERY BAD IF I WANT IT TO STAY TOGETHER!!!<br>So I had to do it in small portions at a time and then let it cool and then move on to the next portion. I continued to do that until the entire mask was heat sealed and OMG it looks so good now!!<br><img alt="heat-seal-my-beloved.jpg" src="\lib\media\heat-seal-my-beloved.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>The heat sealing also slightly changed the color of the foam, but it's not a big deal because the paint will cover it up. While we're on the topic of paint...<br><br>I decided to do what Punished Props did in the tutorial and add Plasti-Dip to the mask. Plasti-Dip is like spray-on plastic covering. It made the foam super smooth and glossy. <br><img alt="plasti-dipped.jpg" src="\lib\media\plasti-dipped.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>After using the Plasti-Dip, I sprayed on some Primer.<br><img alt="primered.jpg" src="\lib\media\primered.jpg" style="width: 550px; max-width: 100%;"><br>After the Primer, I finally started to use some Spray Paint!<br><img src="\lib\media\painted-1.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\painted-2.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><br>While looking for paint references for the mask, I came across the most awesome cosplay I have ever seen that I could use as a reference for the colors.<br>I found <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://instagram.com/phaestoz" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://instagram.com/phaestoz" target="_blank">@phaestoz</a> on Instagram who made a killer Solanum cosplay that is 1,000,000 times better than my mask will ever be. I decided to use his mask as a reference for mine!<br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://scontent.cdninstagram.com/v/t51.29350-15/375181987_830450741927027_648222743865503495_n.heic?stp=c153.0.461.460a_dst-jpg_s640x640&amp;_nc_cat=110&amp;ccb=1-7&amp;_nc_sid=c4dd86&amp;_nc_ohc=ojdAOQG50REAX_buOzm&amp;_nc_ht=scontent.cdninstagram.com&amp;oh=00_AfABch7GA3j4aLMBXxfNmXokItRPLzkkfvSWVFCplwFO5A&amp;oe=657DBAFB');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">Aaron on Instagram: “Had an amazing time at my first dragon con! I got to meet so many amazing people and have great times with friends. I hope to see them all again next year! There are so many people I didn’t get to get photos with, unfortunately, but thank you for making it a great con! #dragoncon #dragoncon2023 #cosplay #outerwilds #foamsmith #starwars”</a>
          
          150 likes, 14 comments - phaestoz on September 4, 2023: “Had an amazing time at my first dragon con! I got to meet so many amazing people and have great...”
          
            
              <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br>Fun SidenoteWhen I was looking through phaestoz's Instagram photos of his Solanum cosplay, I came across <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-" target="_blank">this awesome photo</a>:<br>
<img alt="phaestoz-with-punished-props.png" src="\lib\media\phaestoz-with-punished-props.png" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;">
The two people posing on the left and right are the ones from Punished Props! They're the one who made the tutorial I was following! What a coincidence!!! They're so iconic.<br><img src="\lib\media\paint-1.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\paint-2.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\paint-3.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><br>Here are some pictures of me painting some of the details.<br>I used pastel green, orange, and yellow as well as some gray and gold!<br><br><img src="\lib\media\result-1.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><img src="\lib\media\result-2.jpg" style="object-fit: cover; width: 100%; height: 100%; border-radius: 0px;"><br>Here is the finished product!!! I am so very happy on how it turned out. It took me a very long to make it (almost 2-3 months!) but it turned out so good!<br>After I took the first image, however, I repainted the green and orange to make the colors slightly more pastel to better match the in-game model and the cosplay from above.<br>I made lots of mistakes but learned a lot while making this. I also got a banger new thing to put up on my wall! I'm very happy with it.<br>Solanum would be proud. <br><img alt="solanum-is-just-resting.png" src="\lib\media\solanum-is-just-resting.png"><br><img alt="star-footer" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenDecember 12, 2023<br>Last UpdatedMarch 14, 2024<br>Image Credits<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.metacritic.com/game/outer-wilds/" target="_blank">https://www.metacritic.com/game/outer-wilds/</a>
<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://tenor.com/view/outer-wilds-solanum-spin-spinning-nomai-gif-13075000199548789698" target="_blank">https://tenor.com/view/outer-wilds-solanum-spin-spinning-nomai-gif-13075000199548789698</a>
<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-" target="_blank">https://www.instagram.com/p/Cwyn9GMrao-</a>
<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://outerwilds.fandom.com/wiki/Solanum?file=Solanum_Corpse_Giant%27s_Deep.png" target="_blank">https://outerwilds.fandom.com/wiki/Solanum?file=Solanum_Corpse_Giant%27s_Deep.png</a>]]></description><link>crafts\eva\nomai-mask.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Crafts/EVA/Nomai Mask.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 02:21:57 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Slugcat Plush]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><br>A Slugcat is a cute little oblong creature that you play as in the indie video game Rain World.<br><img alt="Slugwalk.gif" src="\lib\media\slugwalk.gif" style="width: 100px; max-width: 100%;"><br><br>Rain World is a game where you play as a Slugcat trying to survive in a crazy environment with rain that falls so hard it pummels you! There is crazy deep lore that I don't even fully understand yet but that just adds to the fun!<br><br><img alt="Sanshee_rain-world_slugpup-plush_survivor_front.webp" src="\lib\media\sanshee_rain-world_slugpup-plush_survivor_front.webp" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br><br>Because I'm broke null! And also because I want to get better at sewing. This is simple enough to help me get started sewing again.<br><img alt="star-footer" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenMarch 17, 2024<br>Image Credits<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://rainworld.miraheze.org/wiki/File:Slugwalk.gif" target="_blank">https://rainworld.miraheze.org/wiki/File:Slugwalk.gif</a>
<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://sanshee.com/products/rain-world-survivor-slugpup-plush" target="_blank">https://sanshee.com/products/rain-world-survivor-slugpup-plush</a>]]></description><link>crafts\plush-making\slugcat-plush.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Crafts/Plush Making/Slugcat Plush.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 01:11:52 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crafts]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><br>This is a directory of all the craft-related things that I want to write about! Take a look!<br><br>TABLE tagline as "Tagline"
FROM #crafts 
Copy]]></description><link>crafts\index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Crafts/Index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:12:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Manufacturing]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><img alt="star-footer" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenApril 6, 2024]]></description><link>nasa\rsx-2023-2024\manufacturing.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">NASA/RSX 2023-2024/Manufacturing.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:13:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[NASA Projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><br>This is the place where any thing related to my experience working with NASA projects go!<br>I am a member of College of the Canyon's Aerospace and Science Team. Our team participates in 3 NASA projects: HASP, RockSatX, and RockOn.<br>I became a member my sophomore year of high school in September 2023.<br><br>RSX 2023-2024<br>
└── Manufacturing<br><img alt="star-footer" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenMarch 5, 2024]]></description><link>nasa\index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">NASA/Index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:13:55 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Smart Watch]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><br>I really want to make my own Smart Watch! Well, not a "Smart" Watch, more of just a Digital Watch.<br>I just want it to tell time without all the unneeded things like heart rate monitoring, fitness tracking etc.<br>Although I can just buy a normal analog watch, I think it would be cool to try and make a cheap digital one to try out Arduinos and breadboards.<br>Just a thought :)<br><br><br><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77dbz1G_678" class="thumbnail"></a><img src="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/77dbz1G_678/mqdefault.jpg" class="thumbnail-img"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=77dbz1G_678" class="thumbnail"><div title="Getting Started with the Waveshare 1. 28&quot; Round LCD Display (SPI)" class="thumbnail-title"></div></a>Getting Started with the Waveshare 1. 28" Round LCD Display (SPI)<a title="Making Stuff with Chris DeHut" href="https://www.youtube.com/@MakingStuffwithChrisDeHut" class="thumbnail-author">Making Stuff with Chris DeHut</a><br><br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://jlcpcb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://jlcpcb.com/ssr/img/1-4layers.ccaa17f.png');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://jlcpcb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">PCB Prototype &amp; PCB Fabrication Manufacturer - JLCPCB</a>
          
          China’s Largest PCB Prototype Manufacturer, offers 24 hours Quick Turn PCB prototype, PCB assembly and Reliable small-batch PCB production.
          
            
              <a href="https://jlcpcb.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://jlcpcb.com/https://jlcpcb.com/
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br><br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://www.waveshare.com/wiki/1.28inch_Touch_LCD" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://www.waveshare.com/w/upload/b/b3/1.28inch_Touch_LCD.jpg');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://www.waveshare.com/wiki/1.28inch_Touch_LCD" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">1.28inch Touch LCD - Waveshare Wiki</a>
          
          1.28″, 240x240SPI, I2C
          
            
              <a href="https://www.waveshare.com/wiki/1.28inch_Touch_LCD" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://www.waveshare.com/wiki/1.28inch_Touch_LCDhttps://www.waveshare.com/wiki/1.28inch_Touch_LCD
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br><img alt="star-footer" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenDecember 4, 2023]]></description><link>personal-projects\want-to-do\smart-watch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Personal Projects/Want to Do/Smart Watch.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:14:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Personal Projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\lib\media\stars-woo.png"><br><br>This is a place for me to show off personal projects or would-be personal projects! Fun!<br><br>Want to Do<br>
└── <a data-href="Smart Watch" href="\personal-projects\want-to-do\smart-watch.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener"><span class="iconize-icon-in-link" title="LiWatch" aria-label="LiWatch" data-icon="LiWatch" aria-hidden="true"><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="16px" height="16px" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="6"></circle><polyline points="12 10 12 12 13 13"></polyline><path d="m16.13 7.66-.81-4.05a2 2 0 0 0-2-1.61h-2.68a2 2 0 0 0-2 1.61l-.78 4.05"></path><path d="m7.88 16.36.8 4a2 2 0 0 0 2 1.61h2.72a2 2 0 0 0 2-1.61l.81-4.05"></path></svg></span>Smart Watch</a>]]></description><link>personal-projects\index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Personal Projects/Index.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:14:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib\media\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lib\media\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Brando in Space]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\attachments\misc\stars-woo.png"><br><br>Hello! My name is Brando, and this is my portfolio/blog site! It was originally just a blog for Engineering, but I decided I wanted to write about nullANYTHINGnull! (And also as a way to promote myself!)<br><br>I am currently a high school student who wants to pursue a career in Aerospace Engineering or Astrophysics. My dream job would be to work for NASA working on rockets as an engineer or on software as a developer. <br>I have a lot of experience in development in languages such as Python, Rust, Java, and a slowly gaining experience with C#. I am also well-versed in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I have dabbled in C and C++ and I am interested in learning more about both.<br>I have taken engineering classes in my high school and have experience in Autodesk Inventor and Fusion 360. I also have basic miscellaneous engineering knowledge from the classes (e.g. trusses, gears, forces, mechanical advantage) and lots of math experience. <br><br>To put simply: to document the things that I do as a kind of portfolio.<br>If you want more of an explanation, here we go! I was inspired to make this blog to document various engineering-related projects (as well as anything I want to write about, even if it is not related to engineering!) as I work on them. <br>This can be helpful portfolio for me when I apply for internships, apprenticeships, or jobs! If you're reading this because you saw this on an application for one of those, hello! (please hire me :D)<br><br>Take a look at the file tree to the left. It contains all my blog posts, separated by topic and/or project name. You can also change the color theme to light or dark depending to your (YES YOUR) reading preference (the site's assets are mostly designed for dark mode though). You can also see the Table of Contents for each post over to the right. It gives a list of all the headers so you can easily find what you are looking for!<br><br>Brando in Space was a fun name for the blog I came up with because my name is Brando and I love space. This blog is about anything I want, so why not include some stuff about space :^)<br><br>Take a look around! See what I'm working on and hopefully have a great time reading! Thanks for checking out my blog!<br><img alt="Me in 2023 (age 16)" src="\attachments\index\me-wow-but-aesthetic.png" style="width: 350px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
Me in 2023 (age 16)<br>TABLE tagline as "Description", tags as "Tags"
FROM #crafts
Copy<br><img alt="star-footer" src="\attachments\misc\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenDecember 10, 2023]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Index.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 03:06:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="attachments\misc\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;attachments\misc\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Socials]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\attachments\misc\stars-woo.png"><br><br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/brando-higgins" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://media.licdn.com/dms/image/D4D03AQFtUAH_zICx4A/profile-displayphoto-shrink_200_200/0/1703983056380?e=1715212800&amp;v=beta&amp;t=1DMv0J2FKa3KInEFxuJF-zQBXh4pXApVyTNP24nVDF0');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/brando-higgins" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">My LinkedIn</a>
          
          Student at Saugus High School - Thinking about being an Aerospace Engineer or an Astrophysicist - NASA RockSatX Team Member at College of the Canyons
          
            
              <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/brando-higgins" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://linkedin.com/in/brando-higginshttps://linkedin.com/in/brando-higgins
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br><br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://github.com/brandoinspace" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/153570756?v=4?s=400');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://github.com/brandoinspace" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">My Professional GitHub</a>
          
          Hi! I’m Brando. I’m an average outer space enjoyer and a developer and an engineer. Have an awesome day! - brandoinspace
          
            
              <a href="https://github.com/brandoinspace" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://github.com/brandoinspacehttps://github.com/brandoinspace
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br><br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://github.com/BreadcrumbIsTaken" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/63469489?v=4?s=400');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://github.com/BreadcrumbIsTaken" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">My Personal GitHub</a>
          
          hi im brando an i make stuff lol. call me “Breadcrumb” on the interwebz :D. - BreadcrumbIsTaken
          
            
              <a href="https://github.com/BreadcrumbIsTaken" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://github.com/BreadcrumbIsTakenhttps://github.com/BreadcrumbIsTaken
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br><br>
  
    
      
        
          
            <a href="https://breadcrumb.fun" target="_blank" rel="noopener" data-do-not-bind-click="" class="c" style="
                background-image: url('https://breadcrumb.fun/assets/img/blog.png');
              "></a>
          
        
      
      
        
          
            <a href="https://breadcrumb.fun" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="thl">My Personal Website</a>
          
          hi im brando and i make stuff lol
          
            
              <a href="https://breadcrumb.fun" target="_blank" rel="noopener" class="tw _f1m"><span class="twt"></span><span class="twd"></span></a>https://breadcrumb.funhttps://breadcrumb.fun
            
          
        
      
    
  
<br><img alt="star-footer" src="\attachments\misc\stars-woo.png"><br>Last UpdatedMarch 5, 2024]]></description><link>socials.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Socials.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:15:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="attachments\misc\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;attachments\misc\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Site]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br><img alt="star-header" src="\attachments\misc\stars-woo.png"><br><br>This is like a mini tutorial on how to navigate my website!<br><br>On the right, you can see a nice table of contents which includes the heading names. When you click on them, you can jump to that specific heading. It is useful for jumping right to where you want to be and skipping anything you consider as silly jargon :D<br>The right sidebar can be collapsed<br><br>On the left, you can see the site tree. It contains all the pages available for you to read. You can click on the folders and see the related pages. The folders can be collapsed however you want. You can also click the two arrows facing up and down next to the website's title (Brando In Space) to collapse or expand all the folders in the tree.<br>The left sidebar also contains the theme selector. You can choose between light and dark themes. However, this website is made more specifically with dark mode in mind, so some light mode changes may look strange.<br>The left sidebar can be collapsed.<br><br>Posts contain admonitions, or little colored text boxes, that contain special text or data. For example, each post has an admonition at the bottom that contains the date the post was written.<br>Each admonition has its own title and icon, and contains some kind of text.<br>Examples of admonitions you might find:<br>
<br>Written (always present in footer)

<br>Contains the date the post was written (wow!)


<br>Last Updated

<br>Contains the date the post was last updated.


<br>Tldr

<br>To long; don't read


<br>Sidenote

<br>Something unrelated but still related enough to be in the post!


<br>Image Credits

<br>Credits for images used in a post


<br><br>All the pages are written in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/" target="_blank">Markdown</a> using the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://obsidian.md/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://obsidian.md/" target="_blank">Obsidian</a> text editor.<br>The website is generated using the current dev branch of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/KosmosisDire/obsidian-webpage-export" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/KosmosisDire/obsidian-webpage-export" target="_blank">Webpage HTML Export</a> plugin for Obsidian. The CSS isn't directly edited: I add my own header with custom CSS to make it look the way I want. I just override the classes.<br>I also use the following Obsidian plugins that help customize the look of certain aspects of this website:<br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/javalent/admonitions" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/javalent/admonitions" target="_blank">Admonition</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/lucaorio/obsidian-image-gallery" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/lucaorio/obsidian-image-gallery" target="_blank">Image Gallery</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/Seraphli/obsidian-link-embed" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/Seraphli/obsidian-link-embed" target="_blank">Link Embed</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/Meikul/obsidian-thumbnails" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/Meikul/obsidian-thumbnails" target="_blank">Thumbnails</a>
<br>I also made a few modifications to the Webpage HTML Export plugin to let me customize the page titles.<br><img alt="star-footer" src="\attachments\misc\stars-woo.png"><br>WrittenDecember 27, 2023]]></description><link>this-site.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">This Site.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 17:15:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="attachments\misc\stars-woo.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;attachments\misc\stars-woo.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>